when you have nothing left let me ask
you have you ever felt like you had
nothing left I'm not talking about
physical things I'm not talking about
finances I'm not talking about things
you can touch but have you ever gotten
to the place in your walk where you felt
like you had not much left to give this
woman is having this experience she says
I have nothing left in my house save
this part of oil we're not told how she
got into this condition but we know how
we get into this condition you see for
some of us it could be that verse in
John chapter 10 verse 10 where where the
Bible says the thief cometh not but for
to steal and to kill and to destroy so
the reason of nothing left to share when
it comes to your Christianity is that
Satan has come in and he has stolen your
joy ever experience that he's stolen
your peace he's stolen your love he's
stolen your fire he might have stolen
her health or your finances or your
marriage and you feel like you are in
poverty you have nothing left second
Timothy chapter 3 verse 12 tells us all
that live godly in Christ Jesus shall
suffer what persecution but you kind of
feel like man this is too much for me
ever feel like persecution is too much
for you or maybe you have nothing left
because you left it on your own
revelation 2 verse 4 remember the words
of Jesus where he said never
nevertheless I have somewhat against
thee because thou has left thy first
ones love so there was a time that you
were in love with God a time that you
were on fire for God but you left that
first love and it was probably
because you fell asleep proverbs 20
verse 13 the Bible says love not sleep
lest thou come to what poverty open
thine eyes and thou shalt be satisfied
with bread you remember the parable that
Jesus gave in Matthew 13:24 where he
says the kingdom of heaven is likened to
unto a man which sowed good seed in his
field but while men wot slept the enemy
came and sowed tares among the wheat and
went his way so maybe it is just that
you fell asleep and asleep led you to
poverty and so now you come to the place
where you realize you have not much left
in your Christian walk or maybe it is
just that sin has poverty the Bible says
the wages of sin is ones is that sin
leaves you in debt and so your struggle
with that addiction with that besetting
sin that thing that you keep doing over
and over again that you promise no more
no more and yet you continue to do it
makes you feel as if the creditor is
coming to get you you have nothing left
to give
and Elijah's response is interesting
because he says what shall I do for thee
it's like he's asking what do you want
me to do for you because this woman is
coming and crying out because of her
great need let me ask you have you ever
cried out to God or have you ever cried
out in that great need and and and how
many of you would love for God to say
what shall I do for you we're coming to
him in our great need and we wish he
would say these words what shall I do
for you and I want to share with you
listen this is God's promise because the
Bible says in Psalms 18 verse 6 it says
in
my distress I called upon the Lord and
cried unto my god and he heard my voice
out of his temple and my cry came before
him even unto his ears I want to let you
know that when you cry out to God he is
going to hear you
when you cry out to God he is going to
answer you even when you feel like he is
not listening
cry out to God because he will give you
the answer and I'm gonna share with you
right now that if you're here today I
believe God has an answer for you you
may be crying out because of your
experience you may be saying Lord I
don't you know when I first came into
this church when I was first outside I
was just so excited about you and
excited about your word and excited
about serving but now I just feel like I
have nothing left I feel like I'm just
floating along I feel like I am in p'tee
and I need you to do something for me
because my debt is greater than I can
pay in 2nd Kings chapter 4 and verse 3 I
want you to notice this because this is
very this is this is absolutely amazing
eyes I have a very simple point that I
want to get across to you today and I
want you to notice the second cap 2nd
Kings chapter 4 verse 3 then he said go
he said whatever you want go go borrow
thee watts vessels abroad of all thy
neighbors even what empty vessels borrow
not a few how many know the story right
the story right she goes and she she
goes to her neighbors and she's bringing
in all these empty vessels into her
house verse 4 verse 4 the Bible says and
when thou are come in thou shalt shut
the door upon thee and upon thy sons and
shall wot pour out into all those
vessels
thou shall set aside that which is full
now pause for a second does that make
sense who just said yes all right
you're right it makes sense and in a
sense it does not make sense it doesn't
make sense in our human sense but it
made sense in divine sense because all
of this lady has is what one pot of oil
and Elijah says I want you to take that
pot of oil and I want you to gather as
many empty vessels as you can and I want
you to begin to want to pour and I want
you to fill those vessels that does not
make sense humanly speaking because it's
only one pot it's all that this woman
has left notice verse five so she went
from him and shut the door upon her and
upon her sons who brought the vessels to
her and she wants she Ford she poured I
want you to notice something very very
profound yet very simple
this woman was living in an empty house
when she came crying to Elisha her focus
was on her hip her empty house and
Elisha says I want you to turn your
focus to empty vessels i nee I want you
to focus on what I just said I want you
to turn your focus on empty vessels
outside of your home I want you to go to
your neighbors and I want you to get to
get in touch with their empty vessels
and I want you to bring those empty
vessels into your own house see Elijah
wanted her to turn her attention from
her own emptiness to an emptiness
outside of her something in her turning
her attention from her own Antonis and
her own suffering to the two empty
vessels outside was going to be a part
of the process of her healing
interesting the Bible says in Matthew
chapter 10 verse 39 and this might might
really come home to you
he that findeth his life shall lose it
and he that one loses his life for my
sake shall find it in other words he
that does not focus on his own needs and
his own life but focuses on other things
will find his life but he that focuses
on himself or herself will end up what
losing that life Elijah is trying to get
her to focus on other empty vessels what
am i trying to say to you God is calling
you to stop focusing on your own empty
vessel and start focusing on other empty
vessels because in focusing on other
empty vessels something will begin to
happen to your vessel